webjet.com.au 2005-06-18

# Webjet Travel - Online airfares at cost price for all airlines

|  |    |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |   
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
|  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |   
 |   
|   
 |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |   

CREDIT CARD SECURITY WITH _  
_

To ensure the highest level of online transaction security, Webjet operates its site in encrypted Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), which provides the highest possible level of transaction security.

In addition, Webjet has also taken the following steps for your protection.

For all Webjet bookings, Websure protects you by providing a free insurance policy against misuse of your credit card and for non-delivery of any product or service.

Our Internet warranty program is an insurance policy we purchase so we can guarantee if your credit card is used fraudulently as a result of purchasing through our site, or your goods are not delivered, you will be protected up to AUD $4000.00 for any one claim. 

SafeTrade is only available on Internet sites that meet strict security standards and provide you with the peace of mind knowing that in the unlikely event of fraudulent use of your card or non-delivery of goods, you are protected.

Webjet Ensures Your Credit Card Information Is Transmitted   
Over Secure Lines Using Thawte.

Webjet uses a mechanism widely used by the e-commerce communities to transfer   
sensitive data over the Internet called Secure Sockets Layer (SSL).

SSL is a protocol that provides communications privacy, authentication and message integrity and prevents eavesdropping,tampering or message forgery by encrypting data. 

To check when SSL is active, note the following:

1\. Internet Explorer : right click your mouse and select 'properties'. The URL will display for the page you are viewing as 'https' which denotes that the page is secured / SSL is in effect.

2\. Netscape : for version 6.0 and above, those pages that are secured will result in the padlock in the bottom right corner of your browser to close. For earlier versions, the padlock may not change, but, you will get a security alert that you are moving into or out of secured pages providing you have configured your settings to notify you accordingly. To configure those settings, do the following:  
\- select "Communicator" at the top of your browser  
\- select "Tools"  
\- select "Security Info"  
\- select "Navigator"  
then tick the following boxes  
\- "Entering an encrypted site"  
\- "Leaving an encrypted site"  
Also, ensure you enable SSL versions 2 and 3 on the same screen.

Note, only those pages that require you to insert private information are secured.

To make a Websure claim, [click here](mailto:%20mtyrrell@safetrade.com.au) to email SafeTrade and ensure you indicate your booking date and booking reference number.

This privacy policy statement has been made in accordance with amendments to the Federal Government Privacy Amendment (Private Sector) Act 2000 (New Privacy Laws) which took effect from 21 December 2001\. Webjet has consulted with and engaged the services of Gadens Lawyers in assisting us in this process.

**Our Commitment**

This Privacy Policy sets out the Webjet policy in respect of personal information which you may provide to Webjet. Your personal information is information provided to us where your identity can be reasonably determined.  
  
Webjet recognises that your privacy is very important to you and we are committed to promoting confidence in the manner in which your personal information is handled by us. By providing your personal information you agree and consent to the collection, use, disclosure, storage and holding of your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy.   
  
You are encouraged to check this privacy policy periodically, as we may from time to time make alterations, which will come into effect from the time of posting of an amended Privacy Policy on the Website. Webjet will adhere to the National Privacy Principles. 

**Supporting Industry Best Practice**

Webjet is committed to supporting the National Privacy Principles established by the Australian Federal Privacy Commissioner and embodied in the Privacy Amendment (Public Sector) Act 2000. Our aim is to both support industry best practice and to ensure that we comply with principles that form the basis of laws introduced to strengthen privacy protection for consumers.  
  
We believe that in supporting industry best practice this statement will address any potential concerns you may have about how personal information you provide us is stored, used and accessed.

**Information You Give Us**

We collect your personal information at the time you may wish to become a member to facilitate an online purchase and only require information necessary to complete your booking, although you may choose to provide us with additional information so that the quality of service received is improved. Please note that any additional information you provide to us concerning special requirements for flights is only collected and/or used as necessary in order to provide you with specific additional travel arrangements, such as special meals.   
  
Your personal information will only be used or disclosed as is necessary to provide you with the goods and services available through the website, for administrative purposes and to assist us to improve our website and services, and to provide you with information and offers relevant to our services. You may opt-out of receipt of any such offers at any time by submitting a request through our feedback form, or through the methods described in any e-mails we may send you.   
  
We will disclose personal information as required to the providers of the products and services you have purchased, and you accept that not all recipients of your information may have privacy policies equivalent to Webjet’s and consent to the disclosure of your personal information for that purpose.   
  
Where you send us email, use our feedback form, or enter into interactive chat with us in the purchase of flights, we may record this information to improve our service and assist you with any requests. This information will not be disclosed to any third party, except as required to provide you with the products and services you request.   
  
Wherever it is lawful and practicable, Webjet will endeavour to provide you with the option of not identifying yourself or not providing personal information when entering transactions with us. However, failure to provide full and complete information we request may mean that we are unable to provide our services to you.

**Disclosing Your personal Information**

Webjet will not, without your prior consent, disclose personal information for any purpose other than those purposes described in this Privacy Policy to which you have already consented.   
  
We may disclose your personal information where required by law to do so. 

**Cookies**

When you visit our website, details are recorded about your visit, such as time and date, your server address, pages accessed, time spent and type of browser. This information is used in an anonymous form for statistical purposes and as such cannot identify you individually.  
  
We use Cookies to identify your browser so that next time you visit our website we remember your log in details. A cookie is a small file which remains on your computer and contains information enabling our website to recognise your browser. If you do not wish to use cookies, you can adjust the settings on your browser to reject cookies or notify you when they are being used.   
  
We collect your email address when you request to be added to our mailing list to receive updated information about products and specials. You can unsubscribe at any time. In order to enter you into our mailing list, we do not require you to provide any information to us apart from an email address. 

**Storage And Security Of Personal Information**

Webjet ensures your credit card information is transmitted over secure lines using Thawte. Webjet uses a mechanism widely used by the e-commerce communities to transfer sensitive data over the Internet called Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). SSL is a protocol that provides communications privacy, authentication and message integrity and prevents eavesdropping, tampering or message forgery by encrypting data.  
  
Webjet will not be responsible for any access or change made to your personal information occurring as a result of you disclosing your password to a third party, or through any   
unauthorised access.   
  
You can also help us keep your personal information secure by ensuring that any password you use on our web site is kept strictly confidential, and by logging off when you have finished using a shared computer.  
  
Webjet will not be responsible for any access or change made to your personal information occurring as a result of you disclosing your password to a third party, or through any   
unauthorised access.

**Trans-Border Data Flows And Third Party Websites**

Where it is required to provide a good or service which you have purchased, we will disclose your personal information to third parties which may be overseas. You accept that these third parties may not have in place equivalent privacy policies   
  
This website contains a number of links to other websites, including the websites of our commercial partners. When this occurs be sure to check the Privacy Policy of those websites as we are not responsible for privacy policies of other websites.

**Accessing, Changing And Deleting Your Personal Information**

Your personal information that Webjet holds is accessible by Webjet and you with your password or to any other person to whom you disclose your password. You may make changes to your personal information, if you wish, at any time. Webjet relies on the information you provide us and does not collect personal information about you from any other source.   
  
Webjet will retain your information in order to allow you to make future purchases from the Website, until you request that we delete it from our database. In order to request that your personal information be removed from our database, please send your request to us via email by [clicking here](mailto:webjet@webjet.com.au).

**Complaints Resolution**

Webjet is committed to providing customers with a fair and responsible system for the handling of customer complaints.   
  
If at any time you have any complaints in relation to privacy or the operation of the Website, please contact us through our feedback form so that we may resolve them. 

**Further Information On Privacy**

Further information may be obtained on privacy issues in Australia by visiting the Australian Federal Privacy Commissioner’s web site at <http://www.privacy.gov.au/>.

**  
**
